<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Digital Land</title>
    <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Digital Land</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://digital-land.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownfield sites</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/brownfield-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/brownfield-sites/</guid>
      <description>Current areas of investigation We&amp;rsquo;re exploring the following areas to help us learn how we can open up brownfield site data and make it easier to use:
In progress An index of brownfield site registers  Questions we&amp;rsquo;re asking Brownfield site data for local authorities can be difficult to locate and there’s no public register where all local authorities&amp;rsquo; data can be viewed in one place. Would creating a national index of all brownfield data be of value to local authorities and other interested members of the community?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compulsory purchase orders</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/compulsory-purchase-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/compulsory-purchase-orders/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming areas of investigation We plan to explore the following by prototyping tools and by testing and consulting with people involved with developer contributions, and responding to your feedback.
We will regularly add updates to the following issues on GitHub:
 Timeline 11 July 2019
We met with colleagues from the Knowledge and Information Management team to understand the steps we need to take to publish decision letters and inspector reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer contributions</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/developer-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/developer-contributions/</guid>
      <description>Help us develop a common data format In the alpha phase of this project, we developed a new common standard for publishing data on developer contributions.
We are proposing a simple data format for developer contributions that:
 meets the user needs we’ve identified requires minimal effort from local planning authorities to create and make the data available  You can help us improve the format by:
 joining the discussion on our GitHub issues making comments using our feedback form following the proposed guidance next time you publish your developer contributions  We will continue to develop the format as we learn from testing the format with data and the prototypes with users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy performance of buildings</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/energy-performance-of-buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/energy-performance-of-buildings/</guid>
      <description>Finding an energy certificate or an energy assessor for a building is being made easier thanks to a new online service. A prototype being developed by the energy performance of buildings (EPB) team within the Ministry of Housing, Communities and Local Government (MHCLG) Digital Directorate lets users search:
 by postcode or accreditation number for an energy assessor by postcode or certificate reference for 3 types of energy certificate, including the energy performance certificate (EPC)  Previously if someone wanted to find an EPC they had to use the EPC register.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golden thread of building information</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/golden-thread-of-building-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/golden-thread-of-building-information/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming areas of investigation We will be meeting with representatives of the Building Safety Programme to discuss relevant areas of investigation.
Timeline December 2018
We met with the team from the Building Safety Programme to demonstrate the work we&amp;rsquo;ve done so far around developer contributions and brownfield sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing numbers</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/housing-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/housing-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Current areas of investigation The following areas of investigation explore how the data could be used and made easier to work with:
In progress Collecting and publishing housing numbers  Questions we&amp;rsquo;re asking What is the best way to collect and publish data from local plans?
What we&amp;rsquo;re testing We’re focussing on one piece of data from local plans. We’ve now collected the housing numbers from most local plans, and are testing a tool to help us publish this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure funding statement</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/infrastructure-funding-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/infrastructure-funding-statement/</guid>
      <description>Current areas of investigation The following areas of investigation explore how the data could be used and made easier to work with:
In progress How will the infrastructure funding statement be produced?  Questions we&amp;rsquo;re asking Each year local planning authorities will have to publish an infrastructure funding statement. This report will use data that has been published throughout the year (using our guidance) to give an annual summary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local plans</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/local-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/local-plans/</guid>
      <description>Current areas of investigation The following areas of investigation explore how the data could be used and made easier to work with:
In progress What needs are we trying to address through opening up local plan data?  Questions we’re asking To identify what data we want to make usable in local plans, we need to first understand who local plans are for and what people need from them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unused properties</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/unused-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/unused-properties/</guid>
      <description>We’re working with the Cities and Local Growth unit at MHCLG to investigate the best way to collect and publish data on unused properties. This project is part of Our plan for the high street: Budget 2018 brief, which states that “the government will trial a register of empty commercial properties to help prospective retailers to find empty properties and help local stakeholders tackle fragmented ownership on their high street.”</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>