<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Digital Land</title>
    <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Digital Land</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://digital-land.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownfield sites</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/brownfield-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/brownfield-sites/</guid>
      <description>Resources for planning authorities Update your brownfield site data: guidance for local planning authorities Follow these simple instructions when adding new brownfield sites to their registers.
Check brownfield site data for errors Our validator will check local planning authorities&amp;rsquo; brownfield site data for common errors and omissions and fix them. A comparison of data quality for brownfield registers that have been checked is also available.
View brownfield site registers View brownfield site data by local authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compulsory purchase orders</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/compulsory-purchase-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/compulsory-purchase-orders/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming areas of investigation We plan to explore the following by prototyping tools and by testing and consulting with people involved with developer contributions, and responding to your feedback.
We will regularly add updates to the following issues on GitHub:
 Timeline 19 May 2019
We met with the planning caseworker team in Birmingham to understand more about the exisiting and legacy systems used to manage CPOs. We explored what data is entered and how we can extract the data with a view of making it publicly available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer contributions</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/developer-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/developer-contributions/</guid>
      <description>Help us develop a common data format In the alpha phase of this project, we developed a new common standard for publishing data on developer contributions.
We are proposing a simple data format for developer contributions that:
 meets the user needs we’ve identified requires minimal effort from local planning authorities to create and make the data available  You can help us improve the format by:
 joining the discussion on our GitHub issues making comments using our feedback form following the proposed guidance next time you publish your developer contributions  We will continue to develop the format as we learn from testing the format with data and the prototypes with users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golden thread of building information</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/golden-thread-of-building-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/golden-thread-of-building-information/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming areas of investigation We will be meeting with representatives of the Building Safety Programme to discuss relevant areas of investigation.
Timeline December 2018
We met with the team from the Building Safety Programme to demonstrate the work we&amp;rsquo;ve done so far around developer contributions and brownfield sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing numbers</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/housing-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/housing-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Current areas of investigation The following areas of investigation explore how the data could be used and made easier to work with:
In progress Collecting and publishing housing numbers  Questions we&amp;rsquo;re asking What is the best way to collect and publish data from local plans?
What we&amp;rsquo;re testing We’re focussing on one piece of data from local plans. We’ve now collected the housing numbers from most local plans, and are testing a tool to help us publish this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local plans</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/local-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/local-plans/</guid>
      <description>Current areas of investigation The following areas of investigation explore how the data could be used and made easier to work with:
In progress A timetable for local plan production  Questions we’re asking There is no central record of where local planning authorities are in the process of producing their local plans. Would creating one be useful to users of local plans? What would a useful one record of local plan production look like?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single register of planning</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/single-register-of-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/single-register-of-planning/</guid>
      <description>Goals Our goals for this project are to:
 Prototype: Prototype how to make planning applications available as a collection of data in order to show how a beta system with more complete data could work. Inspire: Create, or support the creation of, experimental prototypes of what can be done with this data, in order to demonstrate the potential value of making an open index of this data. Plan for scale: Explore options for how to scale from a prototype to a production system, and the challenges that would need to be addressed, in order to show how to turn this into a sustainable solution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>