<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Digital Land</title>
    <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Digital Land</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://digital-land.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownfield sites</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/brownfield-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/brownfield-sites/</guid>
      <description>All local authorities must publish a register of brownfield sites.
We were interested in learning about how this policy was implemented, the process that local authorities follow to publish the data, and whether there were any tools that we could build to help people collect and maintain the data.
Prototypes In progress A way of validating the collected data   Our hypothesis Through speaking with local authorities we understood that often times the person responsible for collecting the brownfield site data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complusory Purchase Orders</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/complusory-purchase-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/complusory-purchase-orders/</guid>
      <description> Current areas of investigation Upcoming areas of investigation We plan to explore the following by prototyping tools and by testing and consulting with people involved with developer contributions, and responding to your feedback.
We will regularly add updates to the following issues on github:
 Timeline </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer contributions</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/developer-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/developer-contributions/</guid>
      <description>Help us develop a common data format This page documents the alpha phase for developing a format for representing developer contributions as data.
You can help us improve the format by:
 participating in the discussion on our GitHub issues making comments using our feedback form  We will continue to develop the format as we learn from testing the format with data and the prototypes with users.
We would particularly like to hear from local planning authorities who are able to make their developer contributions public and would be willing to participate in our user research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golden thread of building information</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/golden-thread-of-building-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/golden-thread-of-building-information/</guid>
      <description>In the 2018 Independent Review of Building Regulations and Fire Safety there is a recommendation that there is a &amp;lsquo;digital record&amp;rsquo; for buildings. We are working with the Building Safety Programme to understand what a &amp;lsquo;digital record&amp;rsquo; might look like, and how the data could be collected and made available.
Prototypes We&amp;rsquo;ve not yet started to prototype for this project.
Next steps  we&amp;rsquo;re meeting with the team from the Building Safety Programme to demo the work we&amp;rsquo;ve done so far around Developer Contributions and Brownfield Sites  Data fields The specification has not yet defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Plans</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/local-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/local-plans/</guid>
      <description>Local plans are a rich source of information, however once the documents are published the underlying data isn&amp;rsquo;t available.
The Ministry of Housing, Communities &amp;amp; Local Government is working with local planning authorities to design a data format for publishing local plan data.
Current areas of investigation Upcoming areas of investigation We plan to explore the following by prototyping tools and by testing and consulting with people involved with developer contributions, and responding to your feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single register of planning</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/project/single-register-of-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/project/single-register-of-planning/</guid>
      <description>Overview here&amp;hellip;
Prototypes We&amp;rsquo;ve not yet started prototype for this project.
Next steps Data fields The specification has not yet defined.
Publications There are no publication for this specification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>