<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publish your developer contributions data on Digital Land</title>
    <link>https://digital-land.github.io/guidance/developer-contributions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publish your developer contributions data on Digital Land</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://digital-land.github.io/guidance/developer-contributions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 1: Create your .csv files</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/guidance/developer-contributions/create-your-csv-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/guidance/developer-contributions/create-your-csv-files/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Publish your developer contributions data Step 1: Create your .csv files Step 2: Update your developer contributions web page Step 3: Update the national register of developer contributions   Step 1: Create your .csv files To complete step 1 you must be able to create or amend .csv files, for example by using spreadsheet software.
 If you are a planning authority using third-party software to manage your developer contributions, ask your vendor if the software can export the data to .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 2: Update your developer contributions web page</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/guidance/developer-contributions/update-your-developer-contributions-web-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/guidance/developer-contributions/update-your-developer-contributions-web-page/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Publish your developer contributions data Step 1: Create your .csv files Step 2: Update your developer contributions web page Step 3: Update the national register of developer contributions   To complete step 2 you must be able to upload the files created in step 1 to your local authority’s website and edit (or create) your developer contributions web page. If you aren’t able or authorised to do this, speak to someone who is (this might be the person who updates your local authority’s brownfield site register or planning application web pages).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 3: Update the national register of developer contributions</title>
      <link>https://digital-land.github.io/guidance/developer-contributions/update-the-national-register-of-developer-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digital-land.github.io/guidance/developer-contributions/update-the-national-register-of-developer-contributions/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Publish your developer contributions data Step 1: Create your .csv files Step 2: Update your developer contributions web page Step 3: Update the national register of developer contributions   To complete step 3 you must be able to download, amend and upload a .csv file.
 MHCLG will maintain a national register of developer contributions in a file called developer-contribution-register.csv
All organisations with a statutory duty to publish their own developer contributions data should ensure that the following columns in this file are kept accurate and up to date:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>